### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/rebeccawooten-4ba0b537 (LinkedIn) www.wooten-works.com/ (Personal)

## Top Skills

**Statistics** 

Research

Data Analysis

### Certifications

Online Teaching Certification

#### Honors-Awards

Outstanding Service Award Education Excellence Award USF Hurricane Experts

### **Publications**

The Joy of Finite Mathematics: The Language and Art of Math

Statistical Analysis of Tornados Activity by Day of Year in the United States.

Mapping Conic Sections and Estimating Surface Response using Non-Response Analysis

An Introduction to Implicit Regression: Extending Standard Regression to Rotational Analysis and Non-Response Analysis

The Usefulness of Regression in Model Quality

# Rebecca Wooten

Lead Analyst at Wooten Analytics - Statistical Consulting, Statistical Analysis, Statistical Model including both Standard and Implicit Regression, and APPs Developer of Digital Art, Creatives, and Educational Materials

Thonotosassa, Florida, United States

## Summary

The Pedagogue, LLC., President and CEO will be doing business as Wooten-Analytics: Statistical Consulting, Analysis and Research

Has worked as an Assistant Professor for the Department of Mathematics and Statistics at the University of South Florida and has over 24 years of experience teaching college level mathematics and statistics. Worked at New College of Florida, Sarasota as a Visiting Assistant Professor in Data Sciences. Worked at Florida Southern College, Lakeland.

### **AFFILIATIONS:**

Experfy, Boston

International Federation of Nonlinear Analyst (IFNA)
Urban Scholars Outreach Program (USOP), Former Academic
Advisor

Dr. ANV Rao Gurukulam Program (RGP), Cofounder and Former Academic Advisor

## Experience

The Pedagogue, LLC.
President
May 1998 - Present (25 years)
Thonotosassa, FL

The word ped · a · gogue is from the the Greek and translates to the educator.

The word ped·a·gogy is the method and practice of teaching, especially theoretical concepts.

Our mission is to teach the language of math.

You think faster than you speak and you speak faster than you write.

Therefore, the language of math is the ultimate shorthand.

Wooten Analytics
Lead Analyst
January 2007 - Present (16 years 4 months)
Tampa, Florida, United States

Experfy
Course Instructor
November 2017 - Present (5 years 6 months)

**Greater Boston Area** 

Developing Knowledge and Reasoning for their AI track including temporal logical and how it applies to gaming in Unity, and R.

mIQroTech
Artificial Intelligence Architect
May 2019 - December 2020 (1 year 8 months)
Tampa/St. Petersburg, Florida Area

Creating the GUI for clients and assisting in the creation of algorithms to take data from the device into databases; decoding the data into human readable format and connected this real time data to the GUI. After the product is fully operational, will take the data from the data base and statistically analyze and model the 'big data' in an effort to better monitor oil pipelines and reduce loses due to leaks.

Currently on hiatus.

Florida Southern College Visiting Assistant Professor May 2017 - May 2018 (1 year 1 month) Lakeland, Florida Area

Teaching mathematics and statistics.

New College of Florida Visiting Professor, Data Sciences August 2016 - August 2017 (1 year 1 month) Sarasota, Florida Area Teaching Inferential Statistics and work to help develop the Data Science department

University of South Florida Assistant Professor in Mathematics and Statistics August 2006 - May 2016 (9 years 10 months)

Structuring Undergraduate Program, Lecturing and Course Development

University of South Florida

Adjunct Instructor, Department of Mathematics and Statistics 1997 - 2006 (9 years)

Courses taught include: Basic Statistics and introduction to Statistics (I and II), College Trigonometry, College Algebra, College Algebra, Pre-Calculus, Calculus (All-levels), Finite Math, Number Theory, Technology Seminar.

Hillsborough Community College Adjunct Instructor - Intermediate Algebra August 2002 - May 2003 (10 months)

Palmer Tennis Academy Mathematics instructor 2000 - 2001 (1 year)

Florida State University Graduate Teaching Assistant 1996 - 1997 (1 year)

University of South Florida 5 years

Graduate Assistant, Department of Mathematics and Statistics 1994 - 1996 (2 years)

Tutor, Project Thrust 1991 - 1996 (5 years)

Serving students from underserved communities in mathematics, Linear Systems, and computer languages such as FORTRAN.

# Education

University of South Florida

PhD, Statistics · (2001 - 2006)

University of South Florida Master's Degree, Mathematics · (1990 - 1996)

University of South Florida Bachelor's Degree, Mathematics · (1990 - 1996)